Ethan Webb

MSc Student · Statistics

3 The Hastings, Lancaster, Lancashire, LA1 4TF

□ 07745378018 | ■ webb_ethan@aol.com | ■ www.linkedin.com/in/ethan-webb-0294a4192

PROFILE STATEMENT

A Masters Statistics student at Lancaster University who has been awarded the Academic Merit Faculty Scholarship, recognising outstanding academic performance, and who has proactively lead various projects which have fuelled a passion for data analytics and using data to drive positive innovation in business.

EDUCATION

Lancaster University
MSc Statistics
Lancaster, UK
2021-2022

Lancaster University

Lancaster, UK

BSc Hons Mathematics Classification: First Class - 20.9 [/24.0]

2018-2021

- Third Year Modules: Probability Theory, Likelihood Inference, Bayesian Inference, Stochastic Processes, Time Series Analysis, Medical Statistics, Machine Learning, Generalised Linear Models, Additional First Year Minor Physics.
- Honours: Lancaster Scholarship Recognising Academic Talent; Academic Merit Faculty Fee Reduction Scholarship.

Christopher Whitehead Language College and Sixth Form

Worcester, UK

A-Levels: Mathematics - A* Physics - A Further Mathematics - A Chemistry - B

2011-2018

· Honours: Head Boy.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rebrand Project Manager, Severn Rivers Trust

Summer 2019 | Worcester, UK

- Oversaw a full rebrand including new logo, brand guidelines and website. Managed a budget and completed within time limits provided. Adapted to a changing brief, using change control and agile management.
- Appointed a Graphics Designer, negotiating the price down to finish £900 under budget. Guided them to producing a finished logo and brand guidelines that met company requirements.
- Migrated the website to a new platform to save money and improve functionality. Designed and built the website from scratch to meet the brief requirements helping them increase their profile and access to funding.

Work Experience, Brewin Dolphin Wealth Management

May 2015 and June 2017 | Bristol, UK

- Shadowed a Business Development Manager, enhancing my knowledge of wealth management and finance.
- Broadened my network, learnt the intricacies of sales to financial advisors and gained exposure to financial regulation rules most notably MiFID II (during second placement).
- Invited back, I composed a diversified portfolio of Equities, Cash and Bonds for a fictional client, using advice gained from speaking to wealth managers. Presented a written report to my supervisor detailing the risk related to each item in the portfolio and reasoning behind my asset allocation.

Salesman, Bears Great Escapes

Summer 2018 | Worcester, UK

• Sold ice cream on the local high street, gaining valuable customer service skills. Responsible for accounting for the profits of my individual ice cream bike as well as paying licence pitch fee.

LEADERSHIP AND PROJECTS

Quantitative Analysis Team Member, Ghosal Investment Fund

2020 - 2021 | Lancaster, UK

- Recruited by LU Investment and Finance Society to be part of a team measuring and forecasting portfolio volatility.
- Worked in a team of 5 developing an automated risk measure using value-at-risk methods, including a portfolio
 covariance matrix, modelling variance using a GARCH(1,1) model, and Bayesian Networks to illustrate stock correlations.

Project Leader, Enactus Lancaster - Project Recyclone (Became AeroSpark)

- 2020 2021 | Lancaster, UK
- Assembled and lead a social enterprise of 21 students to design a suite of wind turbines and provide the skills and resources required for a Ghanaian Island, Azizakpe, to build their own wind-turbine.
- Communicated with partners in Ghana and established a partnership with a local NGO (Akoma Hearts Of Ghana) to assist with the logistics of turbine installation (remote from UK) on the island.
- Developed a long term social enterprise model, produced a comprehensive set of handover documents, and mentored the future leaders of the project to ensure that the project would outlast incumbent leadership.
- Tackled challenges relating to the Covid-19 pandemic and pivoted the project to ensure progress was still possible despite government restrictions.

Lancaster University, Time Series Course Project

Spring 2021 | Lancaster, UK

- Took initiative to lead a group of 2 other students to complete a course project comparing the Coronavirus time series data for both Germany and Poland.
- Using SARIMA models (to account for seasonality) and an iterative Box-Jenkins model building approach, produced
 models that appropriately forecast future Covid-19 case figures. Ultimately achieving a grade of 90% on the final
 report.

Lancaster University, Generalised Linear Models Course Project

Spring 2021 | Lancaster, UK

- Nominated Group Leader, lead a team of 5 students using Generalised Linear Models to model smoking cessation data.
- Analysed data consisting of 4 categorical variables, to determine significant covariates and factor levels. Built a
 model to predict and determine which groups of people are most vulnerable to restart smoking. Achieved a final
 grade of 95% in our report.

Founder, Wax Works Worcester

2015-2018 | Worcester, UK

 Founded and ran a small candle company. Designed and made a range of Christmas related candles selling them at local Christmas Markets. Achieving a yearly turnover of £400 and profit of £200.

SKILLS, INTERESTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Societies: Member of LU Investment and Finance Society, Lancaster Enactus Society and Royal Statistical Society.
- **Computing:** Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), R (fluent), Python (fluent), HTML (fluent), CSS (fluent), PHP (basic), SQL (basic), JavaScript (basic).
- **Sports:** Played youth football for Bromsgrove Sporting FC, winning the Under 18's Worcestershire County Cup, and for Graduate College at University.
- **Data Analytics:** Member of the "RStudio Enterprise Community", an informal group with over 3,000 members from around the world that meet to share data analytics projects on www.meetup.com. Gained insight into how data is used in a wide array of different industries.
- Leadership and Self-Development: Read over 40 books on topics such as business, leadership and climate change, in 2020-21. Challenged preconceptions and developed a keen hunger for continual self-improvement.